this is a short tutorial explaining how we made the varies of things like fly for our movie "Sintel"
接下来是一个简单的教程 教大家如何制作飞行物体
we have basicly dragons, butterflies, birds
我们有龙 蝴蝶 鸟类
then a large amount of them
很多很多
so we have to carry out with an enfficent way of making a fly in an interesting way
所以呢 我们得想个有效率的方法去制作这些能飞的东西
and for this
这儿呢
we use a library of cycles
我们使用循环库里面的东西
this one is a bird cycle I come up with
这个是一个鸟飞行的循环
it's also one for the baby dragon and for the butterfly
这个同样适用于小傻龙和蝴蝶
for example here is the baby dragon and you will this is the baby dragon with cycles in the character directory
举个列子 这个是小傻龙的飞行循环
btw, in the action list you will find different varies of ones
顺便说一下 这个[Action List]里有很多动作
so anyway here is a small example about a bird flying around the bezier spline
看看这里 这只鸟是按着贝塞尔曲线飞行的
you'll see the banking somewhere you wanna go around it such as connection
（这句话不知如何翻译）
what you normally do is in the NLA
平常你或许会使用NLA
import this cycle you saw earlier
导入这条曲线
and simply go down
打开下拉菜单
and increase the number of Repeats such as the beziered animation
设置好这个贝塞尔曲线所要飞行的圈数
and there have a bird flying around the spline
在这个贝塞尔曲线上已经有一只鸟了
unfortunately it looks wrapped out
不幸的是它看起来很孤单
because the fly's waven
因为它的周围没有同伴
and I really have much characters to do
我得给它添加几个伙伴
and I don't have anything to do with speeding up or slowing down
我不必让这些鸟加速或者减速
as is the part changes
那必须得改一些地方
so I don't wanna change it and I would use these two buttons
所以我并不做改变 并且我要使用这两个按钮
one of these is the new feature for this candidates started for Durian
榴莲项目中这个就是一个很有特色的新功能
Basically it means that we now have the use of a F-Curve we have controls over the timing in the NLA strip
这句也不会...
so basically here you can see
所以你会看到
change the handle to vector
改变向量上的控制点
here you can see it's looping just as it normally would if you would repeat
这你就看到了它一直在循环地飞
the cycle is in a standard wide
飞行路线是很标准的
but because of the curve we now have control library
因为这条曲线 所以我们就有了控制器
so by adding keyframes I can, for example, make the bird speed up as it goes around the curve
通过添加关键帧 举个例子 为了让鸟的速度提升
so add a keyframe here
在这里添加关键帧
and keyframe here
添加关键帧
select to the end and lift them up
选中最后的点 然后让它们升高一点
you now see in that region it will speed the curve
你会看到那个区域里鸟的速度加快了
which means that the bird will fly faster in that region
因为所以 科学道理 这样鸟就飞快了
now just set another one here and drag it up again
另外设置一个点 然后继续调整
so basically the speedy curve means a faster flap a shadowed curve means a slower flap
角度大的曲线飞的速度就快 角度小的呢飞得自然就慢了
as you can see this means that the bird now has a provisional appeal
这里预览一下鸟飞行的效果
and you can make the flap speed make sense to the projectory of the bird
改变了鸟的属性 鸟的速度就改变了
so alright
好吧
this is the technique used
这就是一个新的功能
and hopefully you can find it useful for other themes
希望你能够熟练地运用
good luck
祝你好运
see you
再见